export const GOVERNMENTA2017 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. According to Karl Max, socialism developed as a consequence of the evils of ________",
A: "monarhcy",
B: "communalism",
C: "feudalism",
D: "capitalism",
answer: "D. an institution made up of people with common interest (This is not a defining characteristic of government. Government is about governing a defined territory and its people.)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. In the United States of America, legislature is called the",
A: "Congress",
B: "National Assembly",
C: "National Security",
D: "Parliament",
answer: "B. planned development",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the following agents can be considered as the most effective agent of political socialization? The _______",
A: "family",
B: "peer group",
C: "school",
D: "mass media",
answer: "D. Ecological interaction (While environmental factors influence governance, 'ecological interaction' is not a core subfield of government studies.)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. A corrupt judicial system erodes the observance of _______",
A: "national peace and stability",
B: "the rule of law",
C: "international laws and conventions",
D: "democratic values of the executive",
answer: "B. Fascism",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The body responsible for the implementation of law is the _____",
A: "judiciary",
B: "legislature",
C: "executive",
D: "court",
answer: "D. democratic",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. In a constitutional monarchy, the king or queen is referred to as",
A: "ceremonial head",
B: "political head",
C: "constitutional head",
D: "democratic leader",
answer: "A. Mass illiteracy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Military intervention into the politics of a state involves ______",
A: "an overthrow of a legitimate government by pressure groups",
B: "the seizure of power from a legitimate government by the armed forces",
C: "violent overthrow of a democratic government by the police",
D: "the legitimate seizure of power by the police and civilians",
answer: "D. Common language (A common language is a unifying factor within a nation, but not a defining characteristic of a state.)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Local government are vital in modern politics as they ________",
A: "encourage dictatorship",
B: "train the local people in the art of governance",
C: "make laws for the whole country",
D: "execute government policies at all levels",
answer: "B. people",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following is a civil/public servant?",
A: "House majority leader",
B: "Clerk of the House",
C: "Party whip",
D: "Minister of education",
answer: "D. arbitrariness",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. In a military regime, the arms of government that are usually fused are _________",
A: "executive and judiciary",
B: "legislature and local council",
C: "legislature and executive",
D: "judiciary and the press",
answer: "B. federal system of government",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. A constitution is considered to be flexible if it _______?",
A: "can be amended by a simple majority",
B: "can be altered through special procedure",
C: "requires two third majority",
D: "is difficult to amend",
answer: "A. delegated legislation",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The principle of checks and balances is important because it",
A: "prevents each organ of government from being dictatorial",
B: "frees other organs from judicial control",
C: "makes the organs confront themselves",
D: "makes the government to perform it civic responsibilities",
answer: "D. legitimacy",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following is a fundamental right? Right to",
A: "life",
B: "education",
C: "criticize government",
D: "public office",
answer: "C. unwritten constitution",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Government maintains law and order through the following except ________?",
A: "police",
B: "immigration",
C: "the legislature",
D: "prison service",
answer: "D. can be amended by a simple majority",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. A corrupt judicial system erodes the observance of ______?",
A: "national peace and stability",
B: "the rule of law",
C: "international laws and conventions",
D: "democratic values of the executive",
answer: "A. rigid",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following statements about public corporation is not true?",
A: "It is managed by a board of directors",
B: "It is established by an act of parliament",
C: "A huge capital is needed for its establishment",
D: "It is financed mainly by private individuals",
answer: "D. chief whip",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Acceptability of the government in power by the governed is known as",
A: "legitimacy",
B: "sovereignty",
C: "democracy",
D: "authority",
answer: "C. judiciary",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of the following countries practiced totalitarianism?",
A: "Germany, Russia and Japan",
B: "Italy, Russia and Germany",
C: "Italy, Germany and Japan",
D: "Russia, Italy and England",
answer: "B. impeachment",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. A function of government is _________",
A: "controlling electoral commission",
B: "organizing pressure groups",
C: "making of laws",
D: "forming political parties",
answer: "D. wields the supreme power in a state",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The excessive power of the traditional rulers in the pre-colonial era could checked by ________",
A: "the hunters",
B: "the priests",
C: "children of the chiefs",
D: "the farmers",
answer: "A. collective responsibility",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The post-Second World War nationalism in West Africa was characterized by",
A: "disorganization",
B: "lukewarm demands",
C: "disorientation",
D: "increased agitation",
answer: "D. homogeneity (Homogeneity can actually make federalism less necessary.)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The rights of citizens to benefit from public utility is classified as",
A: "social rights",
B: "natural rights",
C: "religious rights",
D: "political rights",
answer: "A. right",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Which of the following strengthen the power of the Supreme Court against the executive and the legislature?",
A: "Judicial precedent",
B: "Judicial review",
C: "Court injunction",
D: "Oath swearing",
answer: "A. Habeas corpus",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Policy of assimilation was successfully operated by the French in",
A: "Lome",
B: "Goree",
C: "Bamako",
D: "Abidjan",
answer: "C. a broad-based membership",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The theory of separation of powers was propounded by ________",
A: "A. V Decay",
B: "Max Weber",
C: "Charles Montesquieu",
D: "Gabriel Almond",
answer: "C. organizing general elections (This is not a primary function of a political party.)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following is not a method used by pressure groups to achieve their objectives?",
A: "Employing lobbyists",
B: "Embarking on demonstrations",
C: "Embarking on strikes and boycotts",
D: "Contesting for political positions",
answer: "C. schools",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Government is defined as an agency established to manage the affairs of _________",
A: "rulers",
B: "foreigners",
C: "the state",
D: "all workers",
answer: "B. pressure group",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Provision of political education through rallies and newspapers is a function of _________",
A: "political parties",
B: "pressure groups",
C: "educated elite",
D: "the clergy",
answer: "A. pursue specific and narrow objectives",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which system of government has fusion of ceremonial and executive functions as a feature ________",
A: "Presidential",
B: "Cabinet",
C: "Confederal",
D: "Republican",
answer: "B. make the people choose their leaders",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. An agreed set of regulations, conventions and customs by which a country or an organisation is governed is the ________",
A: "constitution",
B: "sovereignty",
C: "suffrage",
D: "culture",
answer: "A. franchise",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. A system of government which is based on public ownership of means of production and distribution is called",
A: "socialism",
B: "capitalism",
C: "feudalism",
D: "oligarchy",
answer: "D. independent of other institutions of government",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. In the pre-colonial era, the breaking of an oath by a chief could _________",
A: "lead to a war with his neighbours",
B: "lead to ritual cleansing",
C: "make his state come under a curse",
D: "lead to his despoilment",
answer: "D. Citizens",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following is not a feature of a state?",
A: "sovereignty",
B: "Government",
C: "Mass Media",
D: "Territory",
answer: "C. civil servants should be loyal to the government and non-partisan",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. One feature of pre-independence constitutions in West Africa is the",
A: "judicial and executive councils",
B: "executive and legislative councils",
C: "judicial and legislative councils",
D: "consultative and judicial councils",
answer: "D. Implementation of policies",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The guiding principle of communism is from each according to his/her",
A: "ability and to each according to his/her need’",
B: "qualification and to each according to his/her need’",
C: "race and to each according to his/her ability’",
D: "age and to each according to his/ her status",
answer: "D. provide utility services to the public at minimal cost",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The political party whose membership comprises people of high social status is called",
A: "religious party",
B: "broker party",
C: "elite party",
D: "mass party",
answer: "D. ensuring the effective administration of the corporation",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. For democracy to be sustained in a country it needs a",
A: "rich political leader",
B: "well – informed electorate",
C: "partial electoral commission",
D: "large police force",
answer: "D. local authorities",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The electoral system in which the winner should have more than all the votes of all the other contestants put together is called",
A: "simple majority system",
B: "referendum",
C: "second ballot system",
D: "absolute majority system",
answer: "B. bring the government closer to the people",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Colonial administration in West Africa was-a result of",
A: "a need for a new environment",
B: "the desire to underdevelop West Africa",
C: "a need for raw materials and markets",
D: "the urge to introduce western education",
answer: "C. Council of elders",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The Secretary of State for the colonies was responsible for",
A: "democratization of local governments",
B: "initiating colonial policies",
C: "fighting for the interest of the people",
D: "working with traditional rulers",
answer: "A. collection and keeping of taxes by the chiefs only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. A political party is significant because it _____?",
A: "stimulates political rancour",
B: "encourages electoral malpractices",
C: "seeks political power",
D: "settles disputes",
answer: "B. inferror",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. One primary objective of the New Partnership for African Development (NEPAD) is to",
A: "settle disputes among African nations",
B: "eradicate poverty",
C: "betray corrupt African leaders",
D: "protect African citizens",
answer: "A. centralized administration",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The crown colonies in the British West Africa were administered through _________",
A: "assimilation",
B: "decentralization",
C: "association",
D: "direct rule",
answer: "C. West African pilot",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. One duty of a good citizen is __________",
A: "building schools and hospitals",
B: "respect of the dignity and rights of others",
C: "loyalty to other nations",
D: "defending a suspect",
answer: "A. Kwane Nkrumah",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. One of the defects associated with most pre-independence constitutions in British West Africa was ________",
A: "veto power of the Governor",
B: "all inclusive franchise",
C: "African domination of the executive council",
D: "African domination of the legislative council",
answer: "D. state",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. An effective way of strengthening societal institutions is through the expression of ____________",
A: "person opinion",
B: "group opinion",
C: "elite opinion",
D: "public opinion",
answer: "C. decress",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. A “Yes” or No” vote on a specific political issue in a country is called ________",
A: "referendum",
B: "public opinion",
C: "gerrymandering",
D: "suffrage",
answer: "A. colonial ties",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Bicameralism is necessary in a federal state to demonstrate that __________",
A: "the executive is adequately represented",
B: "localized interests receive adequate representation",
C: "representation in the upper house is base on population",
D: "representation of the rich in society is taken care of",
answer: "A. colonial ties",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) was formally established in Lagos on _________",
A: "December 20, 1945",
B: "June 20. 1963",
C: "March 15, 1971",
D: "May 28, 1975",
answer: "B. Kofi Annan",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. A political system in which there is only one legalized political party is called a ________",
A: "de jure one-party system",
B: "de facto one-party system",
C: "totalitarian single-party system",
D: "mass party system",
answer: "B. Lagos",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]